《終結者2: 審判日》 153分鐘  特別加長版
Terminator 2: Judgment Day (1991)
Special Edition: Extended Version
2 hr 33 min (153 min)
卡 洛 克 影 業
馬 裏 奧 · 凱 薩
出 品
西 太 平 洋
制 片
亮 光 風 暴 娛 樂
聯 合 制 片
詹 姆 斯 · 卡 梅 隆
電 影 作 品
洛杉磯  西元2029年
30億人死於1997年8月29日
Three billion human lives ended on August 29, 1997.
這場核戰的倖存者
The survivors of the nuclear fire...
稱這天為"審判日"
called the war "Judgment Day."
他們雖然活著  卻得面對新惡夢
They lived only to face a new nightmare...
打一場跟機器人的戰爭
the war against the machines.
電腦機器人的主宰者  天網
The computer which controlled the machines, Skynet...
派了兩名終結者回到過去
sent two Terminators back through time.
它們的任務是消滅反抗軍的領袖
Their mission: to destroy the leader of the human resistance.
約翰·康納  我的兒子
John Connor, my son.
1984年  第一個終結者想殺死我
The first Terminator was programmed to strike at me in the year 1984...
那是在約翰出生之前
before John was born.
但它失敗了
It failed.
第二個則是試圖
The second was set to strike at John himself...
殺害童年的約翰
when he was still a child.
同上次一樣  反抗軍也派了一位勇士
As before, the resistance was able to send a lone warrior...
來保衛約翰
a protector for John.
問題是誰能先找到約翰
It was just a question of which one of them would reach him first.
阿 諾 · 施 瓦 辛 格
終 結 者 2
審 判 日
琳 達 · 漢 密 爾 頓
羅 伯 特 · 帕 特 裏 克
喬 · 莫 頓
阿 爾 · 伯 恩
埃 帕 莎 · 默 克 森
丹 尼 · 庫 克 塞
卡 斯 圖 羅 · 格 雷 拉
特 別 介 紹
愛 德 華 · 福 隆
選 角
瑪 利 · 費 恩
服 裝 設 計
瑪 莉 妮 · 斯 圖 爾 特
配 樂
布 拉 德 · 費 德 爾
工 業 光 魔
視 覺 特 效 總 監
丹 尼 斯 · 穆 倫
特 效 化 妝 及 終 結 者 視 效
制 作 總 監
斯 坦 · 溫 斯 頓
剪 輯
康 拉 德 · 巴 夫
馬 克 · 高 德 布 拉 特
理 查 德 · A · 哈 裏 斯
藝 術 指 導
約 瑟 夫 · 奈 米 克 三 世
攝 影 指 導
亞 當 · 格 林 伯 格
聯 合 制 片
B · J · 若克
絲 黛 芬 妮 · 奧 斯 汀
執 行 制 片
蓋 爾 · 安 妮 · 赫 德
以 及
馬 裏 奧 · 凱 薩
編 劇
詹 姆 斯 · 卡 梅 隆
威 廉 · 威 捨 爾
制 片 及 導 演
詹 姆 斯 · 卡 梅 隆
"體格符合"
我需要你的衣服  靴子  機車
I need your clothes, your boots and your motorcycle.
你忘記說"請"字了
You forgot to say please.
救我呀
Get him off me!
把刀子拔出來
Pull it out!
快拔出來
拿去
Take it.
你不能這樣一走了之
Can't let you take the man's wheels, son.
把機車留下  不然要你好看
Now, get off before I put you down.
這才像話  混蛋
That's it, goddamn it.
六號報告
R-31 David, Sherman Code 6...
六街橋與聖塔菲之間有電流乾擾
at the Sixth Street Bridge and Santa Fe on electrical disturbance.
10-4  R-31  D
Ten-four, R-31 David.
"查詢: 約翰·康納"
"白種男性  10歲"
"前科: 非法入侵  偷竊"
"母親: 莎拉康納  父親: 不詳"
"法定監護人: 柏陶德夫婦"
約翰  快進去把你的房間弄乾淨
John, get in there and clean up that pigsty of yours.
她真是惹人煩  不是嗎?
Your foster parents are kind of dicks, huh?
我真受夠了那可惡的小鬼
I swear, I have had it with that goddamn kid.
- 他甚至不肯回我的話  - 你擋住電視了
- He won't even answer me anymore. - Honey, move.
你得幫我管教他
Would you get off your butt and help me?
- 陶德  - 什麼事?
- Todd! - What?
他有一個月沒整理房間了
He hasn't cleaned that room of his in a month.
原來是急事  我這就去說說他吧
Oh, it's an emergency. Hang on. I'll get right on it.
- 走吧  - 約翰
- Come on. - John.
進去  照你媽的話做
Get your ass inside. Do what your mother tells you.
她不是我媽  陶德
She's not my mother, Todd.
"州立精神病院"
下一位病人非常有趣
This next patient is interesting.
我觀察這病例數年了
I've been following the case for years.
女性  29歲
A 29-year-old female...
診斷結果是精神不正常
diagnosed as acute schizo-affective disorder.
她有一般的癥狀: 沮喪  焦慮  暴力傾向
The usual indicators: depression, anxiety, violent acting out...
迫害妄想癥
delusions of persecution.
但她的心態卻非常獨特
The delusional architecture is fairly unique.
她相信一種叫終結者的機器
She believes that a machine called the Terminator...
這玩意兒的外形和人類相同
which looks human, of course,
它是乘時光倒流機回來殺她的
was sent back through time to kill her.
蠻有獨創性的
That's original.
她孩子的父親也是乘倒流機
And also that the father of her child...
回到今日來保衛她的一位戰士
was a soldier sent back to protect her.
他也是從未來回來的
He was from the future too.
我沒記錯的話  是2029年
The year 2029, if I remember correctly.
我們到了
And here we are.
早安  莎拉
Morning, Sarah.
早安  索大夫
Good morning, Dr. Silberman.
你的膝蓋還好嗎?
How's the knee?
很好  莎拉
Fine, Sarah.
數周前她奪走我的筆
She stabbed me in the kneecap...
攻擊了我的膝蓋骨
with my pen a few weeks ago.
她曾多次意圖脫逃
Repeated escape attempts.
咱們繼續參觀
Let's move on, shall we?
我不喜歡病人把房間搞亂
I don't like to see the patients disrupting their rooms like this.
要確定她有服用鎮定劑
See she takes her Thorazine.
沒問題  索大夫  我會搞定她的
Sure, Dr. Silberman. I'll take care of it.
吃藥的時間到了
It's time to take your meds, Connor.
拿走
You take it.
吃了藥病會好
Now you know you gotta be good.
下午你還要複查
You're up for review this afternoon.
我不想吃
I'm not taking it, Dougie.
- 更不想有什麼麻煩  - 不會有麻煩的
- I don't want any trouble. - Ain't no trouble.
電擊她
Zap her.
快點吃  寶貝
Last call, sugar.
睡個好覺
Sweet dreams.
你是約翰·康納的法定監護人?
Are you the legal guardian of John Connor?
是的  警員  他又惹禍了?
That's right, Officer. What's he done now?
我可以和他談談嗎?
Could I speak with him, please?
他若在家  當然可以
You could if he were here.
但今早他騎車出去了
He took off on his bike this morning.
不知跑哪兒去了
He could be anywhere.
你有約翰的照片嗎?
Do you have a photograph of John?
有  等一下
Yeah. Hold on.
能告訴我這是怎麼回事嗎?
Gonna tell me what this is about?
我只想問他一些問題
I just need to ask him a few questions.
他長得真俊俏
He's a good-looking boy.
我留著照片你不介意吧?
Do you mind if I keep this picture?
不  當然不會
No, go on.
今早也有個人來找他
There was a guy here this morning looking for him too.
對  騎機車的大個子
Yeah, a big guy on a bike.
他跟這件事有關嗎?
Has that got something to do with this?
沒有
No.
不用管他
I wouldn't worry about him.
多謝你們的合作
Thanks for your cooperation.
請插入金融卡
Please insert your stolen card now.
密碼是
PIN number.
快點  搞太久了
Hurry up. This is taking too long.
加油
Go, baby.
好
All right.
- 密碼  9003  - 你這是跟誰學的?
- PIN number 9003. - Where'd you learn this stuff from?
我媽  我親生母親
From my mom. My real mom, I mean.
提三百元
Withdraw 300 bucks.
來吧  寶貝
Come on, baby. Come on!
- 好  - 成功了
- Yes! - Hey, it worked.
好  賺到了  走
All right. Easy money. Come on!
輕而易舉
Yes! Piece of cake.
- 她就是你媽?  - 是的
- Is that her? - Yes.
她似乎很酷嘛
She's pretty cool, huh?
不  她是個神精病
No, she's a complete psycho.
所以才被人關在精神病院
That's why she's at Pescadero. It's a mental institute.
她企圖炸毀一間電腦工廠
She tried to blow up a computer factory,
結果遭擊傷被捕
but got shot and arrested.
真糟
No shit.
她是徹底的失敗者
She's a total loser.
走  咱們去花點錢
Come on. Let's go spend some money.
莎拉
Sarah.
莎拉  醒醒
Sarah, wake up.
凱爾
Kyle.
你不是死了嗎?
You're dead.
我們的孩子呢?
Where's our son, Sarah?
被他們帶走了
They took him away from me.
- 他處在危險之中  - 我知道
- He's the target now. - I know.
他孤立無援  你要去保護他
He's all alone. You have to protect him.
我知道
I know.
你教我怎麼辦
You tell me how I'm supposed to do that.
他對我沒有信心
He doesn't even believe me anymore.
- 我已經失去他了  - 你有能力
- I've lost him. - You're strong, Sarah.
比你認為的更有力量
Stronger than you ever thought you could be.
起來抗爭  戰士
On your feet, soldier!
我愛你  莎拉  永遠愛你
I love you, Sarah. I always will.
- 我需要你  - 我永遠在你左右
- I need you. - I'll always be with you.
還記得我的話嗎?
Remember the message?
一切尚未成為定局
The future is not set.
未來仍可以自己去開創
There is no fate but what we make for ourselves.
別離開我
Stay with me.
留給世界的時間所剩無幾
There's not much time left in the world, Sarah.
凱爾  別走
Kyle, don't go!
凱爾
Kyle.
我的眼睛
It's like a giant strobe light...
感到一陣灼熱感
burning right through my eyes.
但我似乎仍能看見
Somehow I can still see.
老天
Oh, God.
你們知道我的夢境每晚都一樣
We know the dream's the same every night.
- 何必要...  - 請繼續
- Why do I have to... - Please continue.
孩子們像紙一樣的燃燒
Children look like burnt paper.
一片漆黑
Black.
無人倖免
Not moving.
一切東西都被燒得面目全非
And then the blast wave hits them.
像樹葉般四處散落
And they fly apart like leaves.
你的夢把世界末日
Dreams of cataclysm, the end of the world...
描述地很好
are very common.
這不是夢  這場核戰是真的
It's not a dream, you moron. It's real.
- 我知道這一切將要發生  - 你的夢很有真實感
- I know the date it happens. - I'm sure it feels real to you.
1997年8月29日那天
On August 29, 1997...
你也會有完全一樣的感受
it's gonna feel pretty fuckin' real to you too!
沒有擦幾萬層防曬油的人都會很慘的
Anybody not wearing two-million sunblock is gonna have a real bad day.
- 懂嗎?  - 別激動
- Get it? - Stop.
你們無能為力
God, you think you're safe and alive.
你們都會死掉
You're already dead. Everybody!
聽好  你們都會死掉
Him. You. You're dead already.
這兒的一切將消失無蹤
This whole place, everything you see is gone!
做夢的人是你們  我保證  你們若再不清醒
You're the one living in the dream, 'cause I know it happens!
就"美夢"成真了
It happens!
我現在好多了
I feel much better now.
清醒了
Clearer.
沒錯  你最近的態度
Yes, your attitude has been...
的確改善不少
much improved lately.
你說我的生活應該有個目標
It's helped me to have a goal...
找件我很希望做的事
something to look forward to.
什麼事?
What is that?
你說過
Well, you said...
我的病情若有改善
that if I showed improvement after six months...
你會送我到管理較松的醫院
you would transfer me to the minimum security wing...
而且可以讓我會客
and I could have visitors.
現在已經過去六個月了
Well, it's been six months and...
我很想見見我兒子
I was looking forward to seeing my son.
我明白了
I see.
咱們再談談你提到的終結者機器
Let's go back to what you were saying about those Terminator machines.
你現在認為它們不存在了?
Now you think they don't exist?
它們不存在  我現在知道了
They don't exist. I know that now.
你反覆提及砸爛過一個終結者
But you've told me on many occasions about how you crushed one...
那又怎麼解釋
in a hydraulic press.
我若做過這事  應該會有證據留下
If I had, there would have been some evidence.
他們應該會在那工廠找到殘骸
They would have found something at the factory.
我懂了
I see.
你不認為電腦公司掩飾了一切?
So you don't believe anymore that the company covered it up?
不  它們為何要如此?
No. Why would they?
- 換個位置  - 好
- Let's try a new position right there. - Okay.
所有感應系統運作正常
對  這是新的零件
線路有點故障
戴森先生
Mr. Dyson?
材料小組準備要...
The materials team is running another...
- 戴森先生  - 怎麼啦?
- Mr. Dyson. - Yes?
材料小組下午要做實驗
The materials team is running another series this afternoon.
你得簽字同意
You have to sign for the... it.
- 把"它"拿出來  - 好的  我懂了
- You have to sign it out. - Okay. I'll get it.
戴森先生
Listen, Mr. Dyson,
我知道我剛進公司
I know I haven't been here long,
但你是否可以告訴我...
but I was wondering if you know...
告訴你什麼?
Know what?
你知不知道"它"是哪兒來的?
If you know where "it" came from.
我也問過這個問題
I asked them the same question once.
他們的回答是
You know what they told me?
"別問"
Don't ask.
你好  戴森先生
Good morning, Mr. Dyson.
- 還好嗎?  - 還好
- How's it going? - Okay.
插入鑰匙  左向  三
Insert key. Left on three.
二  一  轉
Two, one, turn.
- 你老婆孩子還好吧  - 很好  謝謝
- How are the wife and kids? - Great. Thanks.
好了
Here you go.
你覺得如何  大夫?
So what do you think, Doctor?
我有進步  是吧?
Haven't I shown improvement?
莎拉  問題是
Well, Sarah, here's the problem.
我知道你有多聰明
I know how smart you are.
你是挑我愛聽的講
You're just telling me what I want to hear.
我認為你根本言不由衷
I don't think you really believe what you're telling me today.
你想調到管理寬鬆的醫院  只是想逃
If I put you in minimum security, you'll just try to escape again.
你得讓我看看我兒子
You have to let me see my son.
求求你
Please.
他有生命危險  他需要我幫助
He's in great danger. He's naked without me.
讓我打個電話也行
If I could make a phone call...
不行  一會兒也不行
I'm afraid not. Not for a while.
我別無選擇
I don't see any choice but to recommend to the review board...
只好再關你半年
that you stay here for another six months.
我要殺了你  混蛋
I'll kill you, you son of a bitch!
- 你這禽獸  - 抓住她
- You son of a bitch! - Get her off!
給她打鎮靜劑
Ten CCs of sodium amobarbital, stat!
你們這些混蛋
You don't know what you're doing!
快拿藥來
Get some restraints in here now!
死到臨頭了還不覺悟
You don't know what you're doing!
真是個模範公民
Model citizen.
"目標確認"
你剛好錯過  15分鐘前他們剛走
You just missed him. He was here 15 minutes ago.
- 他們好像要去加利瑞購物中心  - 對
- He was going to the galleria. - Yeah.
加利瑞?
The galleria?
- 我去換些銅板  馬上回來  - 好
- I'm gonna get some quarters. I'll be back, all right? - Cool.
- 噢  不  - 小姑娘  你們認識約翰·康納嗎?
- Oh, no! - Girls, do you know John Connor?
不認識
No.
嘿  你認識這個孩子嗎?
Hey, do you know this kid?
不  我不認識他
Nah, I don't know him.
- 約翰  - 現在不行
- John. - Not now.
有個條子在找你  快瞧
There's this cop scoping for you. Check it out.
- 他就在那邊  - 快溜
- He's right over there. - Split, man.
- 快走  - 好
- Just go. - Yeah.
你在找的人好像往那兒...
I saw that kid...
嘿  你不能跑到這裏來
Hey! You're not supposed to be in here!
趴下
Get down.
先生  你沒事吧?
Mister, are you all right?
你沒事吧?
You all right?
快啊
Come on!
該死
Goddamn!
靠到路邊  停車
Okay, time-out. Stop the bike.
停下來
Time-out. Come on, stop the bike.
天啊  別會錯意了
Holy shit. Now, don't take this the wrong way.
- 你是終結者  對吧?  - 對
- You are a Terminator, right? - Yes.
生化機械  模型101
Cyberdyne Systems, Model 101.
不可能吧
No.
好傢伙
Holy shit.
你真像真的人
You're really real.
我是說
I mean...
你骨子裏是機器人  對吧?
You're like a machine underneath, right?
可外表是人形
But alive outside?
內部是機械骨架
I'm a cybernetic organism.
外部是真皮
Living tissue over metal endoskeleton.
真帥
This is intense.
約翰  清醒一下
Get a grip, John. Okay.
你不是來殺我的
You're not here to kill me.
這一點我知道  那你到底要怎樣?
I figured that part out for myself. So what's the deal?
我的任務是要保護你
My mission is to protect you.
是嗎?  誰派你來的?
Yeah? Who sent you?
是你  35年後的你
You did. Thirty-five years from now...
派我來保護現在的你
you reprogrammed me to be your protector here in this time.
真深奧
Oh, this is deep.
那傢伙跟你一樣是終結者?
So this other guy, he's a Terminator like you, right?
跟我不同  它是T-1000  是更先進的模型
Not like me. A T-1000, advanced prototype.
你是說它比你更先進?
Your mean more advanced than you are?
- 對  它是特種合金製造  - 那是什麼意思?
- Yes. A mimetic poly-alloy. - What the hell does that mean?
- 液態金屬  - 我們去哪兒?
- Liquid metal. - Where are we going?
你得立刻離開這座城市  這樣才能逃避它的追殺
We have to get out of the city immediately and avoid the authorities.
我想回家去  收拾些東西再走
I gotta stop by my house. I wanna pick up some stuff.
否決  T-1000它一定會在那等你的
Negative. The T-1000 would definitely try to reacquire you there.
- 你確定?  - 我確定
- You sure? - I would.
陶德和吉納會有危險
Look, Todd and Janelle are dicks...
我至少得警告他們
but I gotta warn 'em.
可惡  你有銅板嗎?
Shit. You got a quarter?
- 喂  - 吉納  是我
- Hello. - Janelle, it's me.
- 約翰?  - 一切都好嗎?
- John? - Is everything all right?
- 你們都沒事吧?  - 當然  甜心  一切都很好
- Are you guys okay? - Sure, honey, everything's okay.
- 你沒事吧?  - 我很好
- Are you all right? - Yeah, I'm fine.
約翰  天晚了  我很擔心你
John, it's late. I was beginning to worry about you.
你趕快回來  我們一起吃晚餐
If you hurry home, we can sit down and have dinner together.
我正在煮牛肉呢
I'm making beef stew.
不對勁  她對我從沒這麼好過
Somethings wrong. She's never this nice.
約翰  你在哪兒?
John? Where are you?
那隻狗在鬼叫什麼勁?
What the hell is the goddamn dog barking at?
閉嘴  你這一文不值的廢物
Hey, shut up, you worthless piece of shit!
狗在吠叫
The dog's really barking.
叫那小鬼把那雜種狗丟掉
You were gonna tell the kid to get rid of that mutt.
約翰  天晚了  別害我擔心
John, it's late. Please don't make me worry.
他已經在那裏了嗎?
Could he already be there?
甜心  你沒事吧
Honey, are you okay?
- 我在這兒  我沒事  - 真的嗎?
- I'm right here. I'm fine. - Are you sure you're all right?
- 狗叫什麼名字?  - 麥克斯
- What's the dog's name? - Max.
吉納  伍飛怎麼了?
Hey, Janelle. What's wrong with Wolfie?
我聽見它在叫  它沒事吧?
I can hear him barking. Is he okay?
伍飛很好  甜心  它很好
Wolfie's fine, honey. Wolfie's just fine.
你在哪兒?
Where are you?
你的養父母都死了
Your foster parents are dead.
說清楚點
I need a minute here.
你說這機器能模仿一切事物?
You're telling me that this thing can imitate anything it touches?
只要它能接觸到的都行
Anything it samples by physical contact.
厲害
Get real.
那它也能變成一包香煙?
It could disguise itself as a pack of cigarettes?
不行  只能變成類似它大小的物體
No, only an object of equal size.
那為何不變成顆炸彈來殺我?
Why not just become a bomb or something to get me?
它無法變成很複雜的機器
It can't form complex machines.
像槍枝  炸藥  化學品等
Guns and explosives have chemicals, moving parts.
但它可以變出一個固態金屬形狀
It doesn't work that way. But it can form solid metal shapes.
- 像是什麼?  - 像刀  能刺的武器
- Like what? - Knives and stabbing weapons.
"麥克斯"
這些是電視監視器照的
These were taken by a video surveillance camera...
1984年  在西城警局
at the West Highland Police Station in 1984.
那晚他殺了17名警察
He killed 17 police officers that night.
都是有家室的人
Men with families...
有子女
children.
這是今天在一個購物中心照的
These were taken at a mall in Reseda...
就在今天
today.
康納小姐  我們知道你認得此人
Miss Connor, we know you know who this guy is.
我還要告訴你  令郎也失蹤了
I just sat here and told you that your son is missing...
他的養父母雙雙遇害
that the foster parents have been murdered.
我們知道此人涉有重嫌
We know this guy's involved.
此事你一點也不關心?  你關心嗎?
Doesn't that mean anything to you? Don't you care?
我們是在浪費時間  咱們走
We're wasting our time. Let's go.
抱歉各位
Sorry, guys.
她越來越與現實生活脫節了
She's grown more disconnected from reality as time goes on.
恐怕她幫不了你們的忙
I'm afraid she can't help us now.
也許等她神智清醒時就可以了  我會通知你們的
If she clears at all and can give us anything, I'll call you.
好吧
Sure.
道格  請帶她回房去
Douglas, take her back to her room, please.
是
Yes, sir.
我們走
Come on, sweetheart. Let's go.
好長一段時間
You see...
我們曾在尼加拉瓜或其他的地方待過
we spent a lot of time in Nicaragua and places like that.
她有陣子跟退役的綠色貝雷帽士兵混
For a while there, she was with this crazy ex-Green Beret guy...
弄了不少槍
running guns.
然後又找了些人
Then there were some other guys.
她向任何可以學習的人吸取經驗
She'd shack up with anybody she could learn from...
以便將我造就成偉大的軍事領袖
so she could teach me how to be this great military leader.
後來她被捕了
Then she gets busted.
我媽瘋狂的舉動把我也弄糊塗了
It's like, "Sorry, kid, your mom's a psycho. Didn't you know?"
好像她教我相信的一切是狗屎
Like everything I've been brought up to believe is all made-up bullshit.
我痛恨這一點
I hated her for that.
但她說的一切都是真的
But everything she said was true.
她知道的
She knew...
但沒人肯相信她
and nobody believed her...
連我在內
not even me.
我們得把她弄出醫院
Listen. We gotta get her out of there.
否決  T-1000精明狡猾
Negative. The T-1000's highest probability for success now...
現在可能已經變成莎拉·康納  等你去自投羅網
will be to copy Sarah Connor and wait for you to make contact with her.
那她會怎樣?
Great. What happens to her?
模仿的對象必須消滅
Typically, the subject being copied is terminated.
糟了  你怎麼不早說?  我們得馬上走
Shit! Why didn't you tell me? We gotta go right now!
否決  這不是我任務的重點
Negative. It's not a mission priority.
但這是我的重點
Fuck you! She's a priority to me!
混蛋  你是怎麼回事?  救命
Goddamn it! What's your problem? Help!
這對我們的任務毫無用處
This does not help our mission.
救命  把這瘋子趕走
Get this psycho off of me! Help!
救命  救命呀  他要綁架我  把這瘋子趕走
I'm being kidnapped! Get this psycho off of me!
放手
Let me go!
你為何那樣做?
Why did you do that?
因為你命令我"放手"
Because you told me to.
什麼?
What?
你得照我的話去做  對吧?
You have to do what I say?
那是我任務的一個最高原則
That's one of my mission parameters.
證明呀  用一隻腳站立
Prove it. Stand on one foot.
好
Yes!
真酷  只聽我命令的終結者
Cool. My own Terminator. Wow.
你沒事吧  孩子?
You okay, kid?
滾開  別煩我
Take a hike, bozo.
我們別插手啦
Let's get outta here, man.
去你的  混球
Fuck you, you little dipshit!
混球?
Dipshit?
把腳放下
Put your leg down.
- 你敢叫我混球  - 只是想幫忙
- Did you call moi a dipshit? - Just trying to help this punk.
給這小子點顏色瞧瞧
Grab this guy.
放開我
Get him off of me!
現在誰是混球?
Now who's the dipshit...
- 你個草包  - 放手
- you jock douche bag? - Get off!
不
No.
把槍放下  快
Put the gun down now!
- 離開這兒  - 兄弟  咱們快走
- Get outta here! - Come on. Let's split!
天呀  你會把那人給殺了
You were gonna kill that guy!
當然  我是終結者
Of course. I'm a Terminator.
仔細聽我說  好嗎?
Listen to me very carefully, okay?
你現在不再是終結者  好嗎?
You're not a Terminator anymore, all right?
聽懂了嗎?
You got that?
你就是不能隨便到處殺人
You just can't go around killing people.
為什麼?
Why?
什麼意思?  反正就是不行
What do you mean, why? 'Cause you can't.
為什麼?
Why?
因為你就是不能  好嗎?  這件事你得信任我
Because you just can't, okay? Trust me on this.
我要去救我媽
Look. I'm gonna go get my mom.
我命令你要協助我
I order you to help me.
莎拉·康納在這裏嗎?
You have a Sarah Connor here?
你來遲了  是嗎?
You're runnin' kind of late.
他們已經來了一個多小時
They've been in there for an hour.
等一下  我替你通知
Hold on a second. I'll buzz you in.
你的朋友來了
Oh, here come your friends now.
- 葛蘭  要咖啡嗎?  - 不  謝了
- Gwen, you want some coffee? - No, thanks.
- 來杯啤酒吧?  - 真愛說笑
- How 'bout a beer? - Yeah, right.
- 我中獎了  - 那可真棒
- Hey, I got a full house. - That's good, Louis.
我走運了
Must be my lucky day.
你說得沒錯
You're right about number 24.
給24號病房增加藥劑量吧
Increase the medication to 250 milligrams.
- 還用同一種藥嗎?  - 對
- Same kind? - Mm-hmm.
你
You!
你弄斷我的手臂了
You broke my arm.
人體內有215塊骨頭
There are 215 bones in the human body.
不過是斷一根而已  不准動
That's one. Now, don't move.
"排水管洗潔劑  有毒"
你想幹什麼?
What are you going to do?
我們停下來幹什麼?
Why do we stop now?
你得保證絕不殺人  好嗎?
You gotta promise me you're not gonna kill anyone, right?
- 好  - 你發誓
- Right. - Swear?
什麼?
What?
舉手說  "我絕不殺人"
Just put up your hand and say, "I swear I won't kill anyone."
我發誓我不殺任何人
I swear I will not kill anyone.
好  咱們走
All right. Let's go.
會客時間是十點到四點
Visiting hours is 10:00 to 4:00...
週一到週五
Monday through Friday.
你在幹什麼?
What are you doing?
王八蛋  你開槍打我
You son of a bitch! You shot me!
瘋子
Crazy bastard!
別再開槍了  別殺我
Don't shoot me again. Don't kill me.
他死不了的
He'll live.
婊子養的
Son of a bitch!
大家別激動
Let's try to remain calm.
開門  否則他死定了
Open it, or he'll be dead before he hits the floor.
你逃不了的  放開他
There's no way, Connor. Let him go.
- 把門打開  - 否則會怎樣?
- Open the door. - It ain't gonna happen.
別緊張
Take it easy, Sarah.
行不通的  我知道你不是殺手
It won't work. You're no killer. I don't believe you can do it.
反正你們都得死  索大夫  你知道我很認真
You're already dead. Everybody dies. You know I believe it.
別跟我耍花招
So don't fuck with me!
開門
Open the door!
快開門
退後
Back off!
退回去
Get back!
我會讓他死翹翹  我保證
I'll pump him full of this shit. I swear!
退後
Back!
別動
Don't move!
丟掉木棍
Drop the shit!
照做
Do it!
讓開
Get in the office.
趴在地上  臉朝下  你過來
On the floor, face down. Not you!
把門打開
Open the door.
趴下  拉好門  面對牆壁
On the floor. Hold it open. Face the wall!
抓住她
Get her!
快打開
Hurry up! Open the door! The door's locked!
快
Let's go! Open it!
- 鎖被弄壞了  - 想辦法打開
- She broke it off. - Open it!
往那邊  快追
Let's go around! Come on! Move it!
不
No.
不
媽  等等
Mom, wait!
休想逃走
Come back here!
不
No.
- 救她呀  - 你別來
- Help her! - Wait here.
- 快幫忙  - 他會把我們都殺死的
- Hurry up! - He'll kill us all!
拉住她
Hold her.
他會殺死我們的
He'll kill us all!
媽  你沒事吧  媽
Mom, are you okay? Mom!
想活命就跟我走
Come with me if you want to live.
不要緊  媽  他是來幫忙的
It's okay, Mom. He's here to help.
快走
Go.
它是什麼東西?  這到底是怎麼回事?
What the fuck is it? What the fuck is going on?
趴下
Get down.
媽
Mon.
下車
Out of the car!
立刻下車
Right now!
走
Go!
子彈沒了
I'm out.
- 快點  - 給
- Come on. - Here.
裝彈
Reload.
最後一個
Last one!
抓牢
Hang on.
好了
Ready!
約翰
John.
你來開
You, drive.
甩掉他了  後面沒人
He's not back there. There's nobody behind us.
- 你沒事吧?  - 沒事
- Are you all right? - Yeah.
你看的到路?
Can you see anything?
我看的一清二楚
I see everything.
"路況能見度提升"
酷
Cool.
過來
Come here.
我說過我沒事
I said I was okay.
約翰  你來找我真是愚蠢
John, it was stupid of you to go there.
你該有自知之明的
You have to be smarter than that.
你差點連命都送掉
You were almost killed.
你到底在想什麼?
What were you thinking?
你不該冒險  為我也不行
You cannot risk yourself, even for me.
你的命太重要了
Do you understand? You're too important.
你懂嗎?
Do you understand?
可是...
But...
我必須把你從那兒就出來  對不起
I had to get you out of that place. I'm sorry.
我不需要你協助  我自有辦法
I didn't need your help. I can take care of myself.
你的眼睛怎麼了?
What's wrong with your eyes?
沒什麼
Nothing.
你又是什麼來頭?
So, what's your story?
你沒事?
You okay?
很好
Fine.
這機車真不錯
Say, that's a nice bike.
輕點行嗎?  老粗
Watch it, lug nuts.
你知道自己在幹什麼嗎?
Listen, do you know what you're doing?
我對人體構造非常瞭解
I have detailed files on human anatomy.
我想也是
I bet.
那使你更容易殺人  是吧?
Makes you a more efficient killer, right?
沒錯
Correct.
你被擊中時會痛嗎?
Does it hurt when you get shot?
我感到受損  亦可稱為"疼痛"
I sense injuries. The data could be called "pain."
約翰  幫我調整燈光
John, help me with the light.
- 會痊瘉嗎?  - 會的
- Will these heal up? - Yes.
那就好  你若不像人  對我們就沒用
Good. If you can't pass for human, you're not much good to us.
你能活多久?
How long do you live? I mean, last. Whatever.
我的電池可維持120年
A hundred and twenty years with my existing power cell.
你能學習你電腦中還未輸入過的事嗎?
Can you learn stuff that you haven't been programmed with...
使你能夠
so you can be...
更像人類?
you know, more human...
這樣你才不會像個傻蛋
and not such a dork all the time?
我的中央處理器是神經元處理器  也是學習型電腦
My CPU is a neural net processor, a learning computer.
我們外出時天網會將開關設置為"只可讀取"
But Skynet presets the switch to read-only when we're sent out alone.
它不想讓你有其他思想?
Doesn't want you to do too much thinking, huh?
不可以
No.
能重新設定嗎?
Can we reset the switch?
把轉子逆時針轉動
Rotate the two locking cylinders counterclockwise.
動手
Do it.
把蓋子扭開
Now open the port cover.
用力拔出來
Pull to break the seal.
現在把芯片取出來
Good, now remove the shock-damping assembly.
可以看到中央處理器了
You can now access the CPU.
- 看見了嗎?  - 看見了
- Do you see it? - Yes.
鉗住處理器突起部分
Hold the CPU by its base tab.
"槽口打開"
拔出來
Pull.
看見開關了嗎?
Do you see the pin switch?
不要
No! No!
- 與你無關  - 別毀滅他
- Out of my way, John. - Don't kill him.
是"它"  不是"他"  "它"
It, John, not him. It.
好的  是"它"  但我們需要"它"
Okay, it. But we need it.
好好聽我說
Listen to me. You listen.
依靠自己的力量比較好
We're better off on our own.
可他是證據
But he's the only proof we have...
是戰爭以及未來之事的唯一證據
of the future and the war and all that.
也許
Maybe.
可我始終信不過它
I don't trust it.
他是我的朋友  對吧?
But he's my friend, all right?
你根本不知道"它"到底要殺誰
You don't know what it's like to try to kill one of these things...
為了以防萬一  這是最後機會  動手吧
and if something goes wrong this could be our last chance, so move!
如果我真是未來領袖
If I'm ever supposed to be this great military leader...
那你總該聽一次領袖的意見吧?
maybe you should start listening to my leadership ideas once in a while.
如果親生母親都不聽我的話
Because if my own mother won't,
那又怎能指望別人?
how do you expect anyone else to?
好吧  聽你的吧
All right, play it your way.
"系統中斷"
"診斷"
有問題嗎?
Was there a problem?
沒問題
No problem.
即便有  我也擺平了
None whatsoever.
現在開始學習吧
Are we learning yet?
我們得盡量遠離這座城市
We have to get as far away from the city as possible.
往南走
Just head south.
時速別超過65英里
Keep it under 65.
- 否則會被交警攔下  - 確認
- We don't want to be pulled over. - Affirmative.
不  不不
No, no, no.
你得學人類說話的方式
You gotta listen to the way people talk.
你不能說"確認"那種鳥話
You don't say "affirmative" or some shit like that.
你要說  "沒問題"
You say, "No problemo."
如果有人找碴  你就說  "有種試試看"
If someone comes off to you with an attitude, you say, "Eat me."
如果要解決掉他們  就說"拜拜了  寶貝"
And if you want to shine them on, it's "Hasta la vista, baby."
拜拜了  寶貝
Hasta la vista, baby.
對  或者說  "去死吧  精蟲"
Yeah, or "Later, dick-wad."
有人生氣  你就說  "冷靜點"
If someone gets upset, you say, "Chill out."
或者你也可以自由發揮
Or you can do combinations.
冷靜點  精蟲
Chill out, dick-wad.
對  看  你真的會了
That's great. See? You're getting it.
沒問題
No problemo.
你身上帶錢了嗎?
You got any cash?
有幾百塊  分你一半
I got a couple hundred bucks. I'll give you half.
媽
Mom!
我去買點吃的
Get some food.
一點幽默感都沒有
No sense of humor.
還有件事  你要放鬆點
That's another thing. You can lighten up a bit yourself.
一本正經已經很老土了
This severe routine is getting old, okay.
你得這學著風趣一點
I mean, you're acting like such a geek.
時常微笑一下
Smile once in a while.
微笑
Smile?
對  微笑  看著
Yeah, you know, smile. Watch.
嗨  真是個好地方  生意不錯吧?
Hi. Nice place you got here. How's business?
別搗亂
Give me a break.
演砸了
Okay, bad example.
看見那個小伙子了嗎?
See that guy over there?
那就是微笑
That's a smile.
"動作選擇"
"分析"
不錯
That's good.
找個鏡子多練習一下吧
Maybe you could practice in front of a mirror or something.
要吃點薯條嗎?
Want some of my fries?
- 你需要幫忙嗎?  - 不用
- Need any help? - No.
- 我殺死你了  - 不  你沒有
- I got you! - No, you didn't!
- 你死了  - 才沒有呢
去你的  混球
I got you!
我們撐不過去  對吧
We're not gonna make it, are we?
我是指人類
People, I mean.
你們天性便有自我毀滅傾向
It's in your nature to destroy yourselves.
對  真無聊  是吧?
Yeah. Major drag, huh?
快住手  要不掐斷你們脖子
Break it up before I wring both of your necks.
我要知道"天網"系統的起源
I need to know how Skynet gets built.
是誰研究出來的?
Who's responsible?
直接負責的人是莫斯·戴森
The man most directly responsible is Miles Bennett Dyson.
誰呀?
Who is that?
塞柏電腦公司特別企劃室主任
He's the director of special projects at Cyberdyne Systems Corporation.
為何是他?
Why him?
數月內他會研製出新型微電腦
In a few months, he creates a revolutionary type of microprocessor.
然後呢?
Go on. Then what?
三年內塞柏會成為軍方電腦來源
In three years Cyberdyne will become the largest supplier...
負責高階研發
of military computer systems.
所有轟炸機都會裝載塞柏的電腦系統
All Stealth bombers are upgraded with Cyberdyne computers...
成為無人操作機型
becoming fully unmanned.
然後它創造了完美的運作記錄
Afterwards they fly with a perfect operational record.
天網計劃法案正式通過
The Skynet funding bill is passed.
1997年8月4日  電腦系統上線
The system goes on-line on August 4, 1997.
它迅速掌握戰略防衛系統
Human decisions are removed from strategic defense.
天網電腦以極快速度吸取經驗
Skynet begins to learn at a geometric rate.
它產生自我意識  時間為8月29日上午2時14分
It becomes self-aware at 2:14 a.m. Eastern time, August 29.
人類驚慌失措  準備應變
In a panic, they try to pull the plug.
- 但天網卻先發制人  - 是的
- Skynet fights back. - Yes.
它向俄羅斯境內目標發射飛彈
It launches its missiles against the targets in Russia.
為何攻擊俄國?  他們現在不是我們的朋友嗎?
Why attack Russia? Aren't they our friends now?
天網知道俄方反擊便可消滅美國
Skynet knows the Russian counterattack will eliminate its enemies over here.
天啦
Jesus.
你對戴森瞭解多少?
How much do you know about Dyson?
我有他的詳細資料
I have detailed files.
我要知道一切
I want to know everything.
他的長相  住址  一切
What he looks like, where he lives, everything.
莫斯
Miles.
你打算工作一整天嗎?
Are you going to work all day?
對不起  這玩意兒很傷腦筋
I'm sorry, baby. But this thing is just kicking my ass.
今天是禮拜天
Miles, it's Sunday.
你答應帶孩子去水上樂園的
You promised to take the kids to Raging Waters today.
不行吧
I can't...
我忙死了
I'm on a roll.
親愛的  這東西面世後會轟動全球的
Baby, this is going to blow them all away.
- 神經元處理器  - 你說過的
- It's a neural net processor. - I know. You told me.
這是神經元處理器  可以像人類一樣思考
It's a neural net processor. It thinks and learns like we do.
是常溫條件下的超導體
It's superconducting at room temperature.
其他電腦就像計算器一樣弱智
Other computers are just pocket calculators by comparison.
真的這麼重要嗎?
But why is that so goddamn important, Miles?
我真的想知道
I really need to know...
有時候我真的要瘋了
because sometimes I feel like I'm going crazy here.
親愛的  我快成功了
Baby, I am this close.
過來
Come here.
想像一下  一架噴氣機
Imagine a jet airliner...
上面的機師永不疲倦  永不出錯
with a pilot that never gets tired, never makes mistakes...
不會像個醉貓跑來上班
never shows up to work with a hangover.
來見過這位機師
Meet the pilot.
我們為什麼要結婚?  為什麼要生孩子?
Why did we get married, Miles? Why did we have these children?
你根本不需要我們
You don't need us.
你的身心全在這裏
Your heart and your mind are in here.
可這東西不會像我們一樣愛你
But it doesn't love you like we do.
我很抱歉  真的
I'm sorry. Really.
帶孩子們出去玩吧
How about spending some time with your other babies?
水上樂園
Raging Waters!
在車上等著
Wait in the car.
你真性急  康納
You're pretty jumpy, Connor.
你也是
You too.
約翰
Hey, big John.
你好
What's up?
他是誰?
Who is this guy?
他沒問題  他跟我來的
He's cool, Enrique. He's with me.
他是  包伯叔
He's... Uncle Bob.
包伯叔  這是恩裏克
Uncle Bob, this is Enrique.
包伯叔?
Uncle Bob, huh?
好吧  自己人
Okay.
要喝嗎?
Drink?
包伯叔?
"Uncle Bob"?
你們很有名  都上了電視
You're pretty famous, all over the goddamn TV.
條子就像瘋狗似的
Pictures of you, John, your big friend here.
想揪你們出來呢
Cops are going nuts looking for you.
我需要衣物  食物  和一輛卡車
I just came for my stuff. I need clothes, food and a truck.
要不要我連假牙都一起給你?
How about the fillings in my teeth?
現在就要
Now, Enrique.
你們也去  去拿武器
You two, you're on weapons detail.
走吧
Come on, let's go.
我媽有個特點
One thing about my mom...
她總是未雨綢繆
she always plans ahead.
好極了
Excellent.
這是最好的車  但缺起動馬達
This is my best truck, but the starter motor's gone.
你有時間等它裝好嗎?
You got time to change it out?
- 可以  我要等午夜之後再越過邊境  - 那好
- Yeah. I'm gonna wait till dark to cross the border. - Okay.
恩裏克
Enrique.
這裏很危險  今晚你也得離開
It's dangerous for you here. You get out tonight too, okay?
好的
Sure.
我早把生死置之度外
Just drop by anytime and totally fuck up my life, all right?
我在這種地方長大
See, I grew up in places like this...
我還以為人就是這樣過活
so I just thought that's how people lived...
駕駛著直升機
riding around in helicopters...
學習如何炸東西
learning how to blow shit up.
我媽媽被捕後
But then when my mom got busted...
我被送進學校
I got put into a regular school.
發現其他孩子都在玩任天堂
All the other kids were into Nintendo.
你害怕過嗎?
Are you ever afraid?
沒有
No.
也沒怕過死?
Not even of dying?
沒有
No.
你對死亡從來都無動於衷?
You don't feel any emotion about it, one way or another?
是的  任務完成前  我得保持機體穩定運行
No. I have to stay functional until my mission is complete.
所以死不足懼
Then it doesn't matter.
我也得保持穩定  "我太重要了"
I have to stay functional too. "I'm too important."
很適合你
That's definitely you.
與我媽來往的男人都是怪人
Most of the guys my mom hung around with were geeks...
但有個傢伙倒很酷
but there was this one guy, he was kinda cool.
他教我玩這些
He taught me engines.
撐住這兒
Hold here.
後來他們還是分手了
Mom screwed it up, of course.
她總是在談審判日等等之類的話題
She'd always tell 'em about Judgment Day...
也許直到今天
and me being this world leader.
她腦裏仍只想這一件事
That'd be all she wrote.
請把鉗子給我
Torque wrench, please.
拿去
Here.
真希望能見到我生父
I wish I could've met my real dad.
你會的
You will.
對
Yeah, I guess.
那時我已經45歲了
When I'm, like, 45, I think.
我會派他回到1984年
They sent him back through time to 1984.
天啦
Man.
他現在還沒出生呢
He hasn't even been born yet.
真不可思議
It messes with your head.
- 把螺絲帽給我  - 給
- The other bolt. - Oh. Here.
她只和他共處了一個晚上
Mom and him were only together for one night.
我想她仍愛著他
She still loves him, I guess.
有時我看見她在哭
I see her crying sometimes.
當然啦  她完全否認  她說那是有異物吹進眼裏
She denies it totally, of course, like she got something stuck in her eye.
你們為何哭泣?
Why do you cry?
- 你是說人類?  - 對
- You mean people? - Yeah.
我不知道
I don't know.
他們就是會哭
We just cry...
尤其是"傷心"的時候
you know, when it hurts.
是"傷"造成的?
Pain causes it?
不  那不一樣
No. It's different.
雖然你沒事  但傷心時就會哭
It's when there's nothing wrong with you, but you hurt anyway.
- 懂嗎?  - 不懂
- You get it? - No.
那才像話
All right, my man!
沒問題
No problemo.
擊掌慶祝
Give me five.
像這樣撐開手掌  來
Just put out your hand like this, come on.
很好  拍打我的手  該你了  你來擊掌
All right! Now hit me. Give me five. Do the same thing.
很好
All right!
好  很好  來個高的
Okay, that's good. Up high.
低的
Five low.
你慢了
Too slow.
我是在開玩笑  再來一次
I'm just kidding. One more time.
很好  接著來
Good. Now try it.
來  打我一掌
Now do me. Give me five.
看到約翰和機器人在一起  突然真相大白了
Watching John with the machine, it was suddenly so clear.
終結者絕不罷休
The Terminator would never stop.
絕不離開他  它不會傷害他
It would never leave him, never hurt him...
不會向他叫罵  不會酒醉打他
never shout at him or get drunk and hit him...
或是藉口太忙沒空陪他
or be too busy to spend time with him.
它永遠會在他身邊
It would always be there...
它會拚命保衛他
and it would die to protect him.
這些年來  我遇到過許多男人
Of all the would-be fathers who came and went over the years...
這東西  這機器
this thing, this machine...
卻是唯一有資格當他父親的人
was the only one who measured up.
在這瘋狂世界裏
In an insane world...
這是最佳選擇
it was the sanest choice.
我們來玩玩這個
Hey, let's try this one.
來吧
There we go.
"不是命運"
她叫你們按原計劃向南走
She said go south with him like you planned.
- 她明天會趕上你們  - 媽
- She'll meet you tomorrow. - Mom!
媽等等
Mom, wait!
"不是命運"
"No fate."
命運是要自己開創的
No fate but what we make.
我的父親告訴她的
My father told her this.
是未來的我讓我父親告訴她的
I made him memorize it in the future as a message to her.
算了
Never mind.
整件事就是這樣
Okay, the whole thing goes...
一切尚未成為定局
The future's not set.
未來仍可以自己去開創
There's no fate but what we make for ourselves.
她想改變未來?
She intends to change the future.
對  我猜也是
Yeah, I guess.
糟了
Oh, shit!
- 戴森  - 對
- Dyson. - Yeah.
一定是的  莫斯·戴森
Gotta be. Miles Dyson.
她想要殺了戴森
She's gonna blow him away.
來  咱們走
Come on! Let's go!
快啊
Come on!
事實上  這樣做非常危險
This is tactically dangerous.
開快點
Drive faster.
T-1000跟我一樣瞭解情況
The T-1000 has the same files that I do.
它知道我知道的一切  它還能預測敵人的行動
It knows what I know. It might anticipate this move.
我不管  咱們得阻止她
I don't care. We gotta stop her.
殺死戴森的確有可能阻止戰爭
Killing Dyson might prevent the war.
我不管  你還沒學通嗎?
I don't care! Haven't you learned anything yet?
你還不明白為何不能亂殺人嗎?
Haven't you figured out why you can't kill people?
聽著  也許你不在乎生死
Look, maybe you don't care if you live or die...
可並非所有人都這樣
but everybody's not like that.
人類有感情  會受到傷害  會感到恐懼
We have feelings. We hurt. We're afraid.
這種東西你要理解  我不是開玩笑  真的很重要
You got to learn this stuff. I'm not kidding. It's important.
丹尼  叫你去睡覺  我說真的
Danny, I told you to go to bed, like your sister.
再玩一會兒就好  媽
Just a couple of minutes, Mom!
丹尼  睡覺時間到了
Danny, your time is up!
快刷牙上床
Come brush your teeth and get to bed.
丹尼
Danny.
爸
Daddy!
這不是遊戲  快逃
Danny, go! Go!
莫斯
Miles.
- 特瑞莎  跑  - 我的天啊
- Tarissa, run! - Oh, my God!
快帶丹尼走  快逃
Just take Danny and run!
快逃
Run!
我的天呀
Oh, Jesus! Miles!
爹地
Daddy!
丹尼
Danny.
誰都不許動
Nobody fucking move!
別傷害我爸
Don't hurt my daddy!
趴到地上
On the floor, bitch.
趴下
Get down now!
讓開
Get out of the way!
別傷害他
Don't hurt him!
讓開  否則我開槍
Get on the floor now!
饒了孩子吧
Just let the boy go.
你閉嘴
Shut up. Shut up.
閉嘴
Shut up!
都是你的錯  混蛋
It's all your fault, motherfucker.
- 都是你的錯  - 什麼?
- It's all your fault! - What?
我不會讓你得逞的
I'm not gonna let you do it.
糟了  太遲了
Shit! We're too late!
看看他們
Check them.
看著我  媽
Look at me, Mom.
你受傷了?
Are you hurt?
看著我
Look at me.
我幾乎
I almost...
我下不了手
放心吧
It'll be okay.
一定還有辦法的  真的
We'll figure something out. Okay?
相信我吧
I promise.
你是來阻止我的?
You came here to stop me.
對
Yeah, I did.
我愛你  約翰
I love you, John.
我一直愛著你
I always have.
我知道
I know.
子彈貫穿
Deep penetration.
沒有擊碎骨頭
No shattered bone.
把傷口壓著就能止住血了
Hold here. The pressure should stop the bleeding.
你們是誰?
Who are you people?
告訴他
Show him.
丹尼  你跟我走好嗎?  帶我看看你房間
Danny, I want you to come with me right now. Show me your room.
我的天呀
Oh, my God.
仔細聽我說
Now listen to me very carefully.
戴森聽著終結者的解說
Dyson listened while the Terminator laid it all down.
天網  審判日
Skynet. Judgment Day.
未來的歷史
The history of things to come.
知道自己的研發成果最終將會
It's not every day that you find out you're responsible...
害死三十億人
for three billion deaths.
他的反應還算好
He took it pretty well.
我想我要嘔吐了
I feel like I'm gonna throw up.
你是為了
You're judging me...
我還未做的事懲罰我?
on things I haven't even done yet.
我怎會知道?
How were we supposed to know?
對
Yeah.
沒錯
Right.
你怎會知道?
How were you supposed to know?
氫彈就是你這種人發明的
Fucking men like you built the hydrogen bomb.
也是你這種人
Men like you...
引爆它的
thought it up.
你以為你很有創造力
You think you're so creative.
你根本就不知道創造的意義
You don't know what it's like to really create something...
創造生命
to create a life...
是感覺它在體內成長
to feel it growing inside you.
你只會創造死亡和毀滅
All you know how to create is death and destruction.
媽
Mom!
你得說些有建設性的話  好嗎?
We need to be a little more constructive here. Okay?
我們仍要阻止戰爭的  對吧?
We still have to stop this from happening, don't we?
但我以為
But I thought...
我們是要通過改變現在的事  從而改變未來的事嗎?
Aren't we changing things right now, changing the way it goes?
沒錯
That's right.
本來就快做出超級新電腦
There's no way I'm going to finish the new processor. Not now.
現在一切免談  我不幹了  我明天就辭職
Forget it. I'm out of it. I'll quit Cyberdyne tomorrow.
那還不夠好
That's not good enough.
不能讓別人繼續完成你的工作
No one must follow your work.
好吧
Right.
那得摧毀實驗室的一切裝備
All right, then we have to destroy all the stuff at the lab...
檔案  磁碟機
the files, the disk drives...
所有的一切
everything here.
一切資料
Everything.
我不在乎
I don't care.
晶片
The chip.
- 你們知道晶片嗎?  - 什麼晶片?
- Do you know about the chip? - What chip?
他們把它鎖在金庫裏  是跟你一樣的機器人身上的
It's at Cyberdyne. It's from the other one like you.
第一代終結者的記憶體
The CPU from the first Terminator.
混蛋  我就知道
Son of a bitch! I knew it!
他們不准我們問晶片是哪兒來的
They told us not to ask where they got it.
真聰明的混蛋
Those lying motherfuckers.
它很可怕  但非常先進
It's scary stuff. Radically advanced.
它被砸爛了
It was smashed.
無法運作  但它給了我許多不可思議的靈感
It didn't work, but it gave us ideas, took us in new directions.
前所未有
Things we would've never...
我的工作全是以它為基礎
All my work was based on it.
必須摧毀它
It must be destroyed.
你能帶我們通過警衛嗎?
Can you get us in? Past security?
我想可以  什麼時候去?
I think so, yeah. When?
現在?
Now?
未來對我而言已成為
The future, always so clear to me...
深夜中的一條看不見的公路
had become like a black highway at night.
而人類在未加分隔的領域中
We were in uncharted territory now...
在前進的旅程上不斷創造歷史
making up history as we went along.
"塞柏電腦公司"
你是卡爾吧?
Carl, right?
我一些外地朋友
Friends from out of town. I just thought I'd...
我只想帶他們上樓四處瞧瞧
take 'em upstairs and show 'em around.
戴森先生  你也知道規定  帶客人進實驗室時
Mr. Dyson, you know the rules concerning visitors in the lab.
我需要書面許可
I need written authorization...
我堅持
I insist.
你休想妄動
Don't even think about it.
行了
It's okay.
開金庫要兩把鑰匙  而且得同時插入旋轉
It takes two keys, turned simultaneously, to open the vault.
另一支在警衛室裏
The other one is in a locker at the security station.
吉文
Gibbons?
吉文  老兄
Gibbons! Come on, man!
你不能擅離崗位的
You can't leave the desk like that!
吉文
Gibbons!
糟糕
Oh, shit.
我的卡片應該可以開啟它
My card should access this.
什麼?
What?
- 怎麼回事?  - 可惡
- What is it? - Damn it.
警報器已經啟動
The silent alarm's been tripped.
它使所有啟動密碼都失效了
It's neutralized all the codes in the entire building.
現在到處都不通了
Nothing will open anywhere now.
我們得放棄此事
We have to abort.
不
No.
我們幹到底
We go all the way. Okay?
你們在實驗室開始行動  我能打開這個
You guys get started on the lab. I can open this.
- 是大鬧商場的傢伙  - 是那傢伙
- I think it's that guy from the mall. - It is.
對  是他和那女人
Yeah. It's him and the woman.
立即總動員到這裏來
Just send everything you got in the area right now.
我的私人密碼可能還能通
I have a personal entry code for the lab. It may still work.
沒有用
It's no good.
試試我的法子
Let me try mine.
約翰  小心
John, fire in the hole!
且慢  現在不能進去  火焰啟動了"海龍消防系統"
Wait! You can't go in there. The fire set off the Halon system.
等幾分鐘  要讓毒氣消散
You have to wait until the gas clears.
戴防毒面具
Put this on.
來吧  開工了
All right, let's get to work.
所有管區及可以應召的各組注意
All units in the vicinity and all units able to respond...
在克拉馬街2144號塞柏大廈裏
a 211 in progress, 2144 Kramer Street, the Cyberdyne building.
發生犯罪事件
Suspect one is white female...
嫌犯一為白種女性  莎拉·康納
identified as last name Connor, first name Sarah.
昨晚從州立精神病院逃脫
Escaped last night from Pescadero State Hospital.
嫌犯二為白種男性
Suspect two: White male...
我辦公室的所有磁碟
All the disks in my office...
以及那邊辦公室的所有磁碟
all the disks in that office over there...
還有我桌子裏的所有東西
everything behind my desk...
所有的處理器
and all the processors on my left.
這些東西我們要全毀掉
We'll blow those with the C4.
能不能
Can I...
打攪一下
Excuse me.
那東西能借我用用嗎?
Can I borrow that thing?
我為它花費多年心血
I worked a lot of years on this thing.
123  請再次報告方位
One-Mary-23, give me that location again.
2111  克拉莫
2111 Kramer.
嫌犯攜有武器極度危險
Suspects are armed and considered extremely dangerous.
好了
All right.
7-2-5-6
7-2-5-6.
賺到了
Easy money.
糟糕  不好了
Oh, shit. Not good.
進展如何?
How we doing?
已經定時
Primer cord is set.
再來一桶  再等兩分鐘
One more barrel, two more minutes.
- 我們如何引爆?  - 遙控引爆
- How do we set them off? - Remote control.
輕而易舉
Piece of cake.
- 有人來了  - 是警察?
- We got company. - Police?
- 有多少人?  - 大概傾巢而出
- How many? - All of 'em, I think.
你們走  我來解決這兒
Go. I'll finish here.
快點
Come on.
我來對付警察
I'll take care of the police.
等一下  你發過誓
Wait! You swore!
相信我
Trust me.
窗台上的人
You at the window!
丟下武器  把雙手放在頭上
Drop your weapon and place your hands on top of your head!
老天
Holy shit!
是機關鎗
That's a mini-gun!
- 快走  - 天啦
- Come on! - Oh, shit!
快走
Go! Go! Go!
"死傷人數: 零"
開火
Fire!
同時向左轉
Same time, to the left.
一  二  三  開始
One, two, three, go.
好了  我告訴你怎麼開
All right. In order to get that out...
我們抓住天網的命脈了
We got Skynet by the balls now.
快走吧
Come on, let's book.
停火
Hold your fire!
- 準備好了嗎?  - 好了
- Ready to rock? - Ready.
該走了
Time to go.
馬上
Now.
- 拿著  他們會用催淚瓦斯  - 快走
- Take this. They'll use gas. - Come on.
快去開門  莫斯  把引爆器給我
Get started on the door. Miles, hand me the detonator.
媽
Mom! Mom!
可惡
Shit!
她被困在清潔室了  沒法出來
She's in the clean room. There's no way outta there.
趴下
Get down!
給
Here.
我不知還能抓住這玩意兒多久
I don't know how much longer I can hold this.
是炸彈
Fall back!
大家出去
Everybody out!
炸彈  快跑
Fall back now! Go! Go! Go!
這裏已經演變成戰場
We got a war zone here!
"狀況預測"
眼睛閉上
Shut your eyes.
待在這兒  我馬上回來
Stay here. I'll be back.
趴在地上  面朝下
Get down on the floor! Face down!
趴在地上
On the floor now!
行啦  幹掉他
Okay, drop him!
你拿著
Here, hold this.
走
Go!
該死
Shit!
出去
Get out.
聽著
Listen.
不管怎樣你都要躲好
No matter what happens, stay under these vests.
- 懂嗎?  - 懂
- You got it? - Yeah.
好的
All right.
直升機來了
Chopper's coming in!
是它
It's him.
可惡
Shit!
約翰  趴好
John. Stay down!
媽
Mom.
天吶  你沒事吧?
Goddamn! You all right?
媽  快起來  我們得出去
Come on, Mom, we gotta get out.
- 拿著散彈鎗  - 好的
- Take the shotgun. - Okay.
你受傷了嗎?
Are you hurt?
"液化氮"
糟糕  加油  媽
Holy shit. Come on, Mom. Come on!
- 我需要你的卡車  - 快
- We need your truck. - Hurry!
- 來  快點  - 上車
- Come on. Hurry. - Get in.
走
Go!
搞什麼
What the hell...
- 血止不住  - 繼續施壓
- I'm bleeding bad. - Keep pressure on it.
這樣很奏效
Here. This'll work.
他越來越近了
He's gaining.
加油
Step on it!
- 這是最高速了  - 我跑的都比它快
- This is the vehicle's top speed. - I can run faster than this!
朝右追來了
Coming up, to the right.
小心
Watch it! Watch it!
- 替我開  - 你上哪兒去?
- Drive. - Where are you going?
走左邊
Take the off-ramp.
可惡
Shit!
抓穩了
Hold on!
別停
Don't stop!
一直走
Go straight!
- 小心  - 閃開
- Look out! - Duck!
快離開這兒
Get the hell outta here!
快離開這兒  快
Get outta here! Let's go! Come on!
拜拜了  寶貝
Hasta la vista, baby.
我們的時間並不多
We don't have much time.
咱們走
Let's go.
快點  我們得離開這兒
Come on! We gotta get outta here.
快點  起來
Come on! Get up!
把散彈鎗給我
Hand me the shotgun.
媽  我扶你走
Put your weight on me, Mom.
快呀
Hurry!
忍著點
Come on, Mom.
快起來
Get up!
走這邊
This way. Come on.
不  等等
No! Wait!
等等  太熱了  回頭
Wait. No. No. It's too hot. Go back.
- 快跑  - 不  我們得一起走
- Go. Run. - No! We gotta stick together.
約翰  快走
John, you've got to go now.
- 約翰  - 快走
- John! - Go! Now!
不
No!
"目標搜尋"
爬上去
Get up the steps.
上去
Go.
快
Get up.
抓牢  我扶你  快
Come on, Mom. I got you.
抓住鏈子  抓好
Grab the chain. Grab it.
抓住它  快走
Grab it. Go. Go!
媽  快來啊
Mom, come on! Mom!
把約翰叫來
Call to John.
不
No!
我知道這樣很痛
I know this hurts.
把他叫來
Call John.
快叫約翰過來
Call to John now.
去你的
Fuck you.
"備用能源"
約翰
John.
救命
Help!
約翰
John.
媽
Mom.
- 救我  - 讓開  約翰
- Help me. - Get out of the way, John.
約翰
John! John!
開槍
Shoot!
媽
Mom!
趴下
Get down!
起來  加油
Get up. Come on.
天呀
Holy shit.
我需要療養
I need a vacation.
它死了嗎?
Is it dead?
被終結掉了
Terminated.
這個也丟掉?
Will this melt in there?
對  丟下去
Yes. Throw it in.
再見
Adios.
還有晶片
And the chip.
結束了
It's over.
不
No.
還有一個晶片
There's one more chip.
它也得摧毀掉
And it must be destroyed also.
給
Here.
我不能終結我自己  你得把我放到下面的鋼水裏去
I cannot self-terminate. You must lower me into the steel.
不
No.
抱歉  約翰
I'm sorry, John. I'm sorry.
不  你留在我們身邊不要緊的
No, it'll be okay. Stay with us.
- 沒關係的  - 我必須離開
- It'll be okay. - I have to go away.
不  別這樣  請別走
No, don't do it. Please, don't go.
我必須離開
I must go away, John.
不
No!
不  等等
No, wait.
- 你不必這樣做  - 抱歉
- You don't have to do this. - I'm sorry.
不  別這樣  別走
No, don't do it! Don't go!
這一切必須結束
It has to end here.
我命令你不要走
I order you not to go!
我現在知道你們為什麼會哭了
I know now why you cry.
但那是我永遠做不到的事
But it's something I can never do.
再見
Good-bye.
不可知的未來在我們面前展開
The unknown future rolls toward us.
我頭一次充滿希望的面對它
I face it for the first time with a sense of hope.
全因為一台機器  一名終結者
Because if a machine, a Terminator...
它學到了人類生命的價值
can learn the value of human life...
也許我們也辦的到
maybe we can too.